Guide to the Richard and Mildred Crooks Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Sound recordings
  - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lieder, op. 48. Traum, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 10 in. (disc broken) (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lieder, op. 48. Traum, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 10 in. (disc broken) (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Aug. 30, 1943, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in. (disc broken) (Box 6, Folder 150)
    There is no death
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Part FourDec.20, 1943, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in. (disc broken) (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - I'll take you home again Kathleen, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 10 in (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Messiah. Comfort ye, my people June 8, 1942, Test pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - Harvey S. Firestone Memorial Program Feb. 14, 1938, Special pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 155)
    Part 1: Strauss, Johann, 1804-1849. An der schönen, blauen Donau. Symphony orchestra. Wallenstein Alfred, conductor Part 4: Tribute by the revered Doctor Walter F. Tunks
  - Harvey S. Firestone Memorial Program Feb. 14, 1938, Special pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 156)
    Part 2: Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. An der schönen, blauen Donau. Symphony orchestra. Wallenstein Alfred, conductor -- Songs my mother taught mePart 5: Tribute by the revered Doctor Walter F. Tunks -- Jesus calls us
  - Harvey S. Firestone Memorial Program Feb. 14, 1938, Special pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 157)
    Part 3: Firestone, Idabelle. In my gardenPart 6: Open the gates of the temple -- I know that my redeemer liveth
  - Harvey S. Firestone Memorial Program Feb. 14, 1938, Special pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 158)
    Part 7: Lost chord
  - Voice of Firestone. Tenth Anniversary Program.Dec. 5, 1938, Special pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 159)
    Part 1: Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. Marcia trionfale. Symphony orchestra. Wallenstein Alfred, conductor.Part 4: Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Ave Maria (Vocal version)
  - Voice of Firestone. Tenth Anniversary Program.Dec. 5, 1938, Special pressing disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 161)
    Part 2: Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. DreamPart 5: Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. G'schichten aus dem Wienerwald. Symphony orchestra. Wallenstein Alfred, conductor
  - Easter and Songs: My mother, Transcription disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 16, Folder 162)
  - Mail Call with Richard Crooks, Test pressing disc: ? rpm, shellac; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 163)
  - Voice of Firestone. Christmas 1943 radio broadcast with Richard Crooks.Dec. 20, 1943, Limited edition disc: 33 1/3 rpm, plastic; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 164)
    Side 1: If I could tell you -- Jingle Bells -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Dance of the sugar plum fairy -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Toy Trumpet -- Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856. Cantique de Noël -- White Christmas -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Romansy, op. 26. K detyam Side 2: Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Herz und Mund und Tat und Leben, BWV 147. Jesus bleibet meine Freude -- Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Stille Nacht, heilige Nacht -- Adeste Fideles -- Lord's prayer -- Dresden Amen
  - Antheil, George, 1900-1959. Capital of the world Dec. 20, 1943, Commercial disc (Capitol P8278): 33 1/3 rpm, plastic; 12 in (Box 16, Folder 165)
    With handwritten dedication by composer: "To my beloved childhood friends, in memory of our youthful dreams in Trenton, with love George Antheil. L.A. 1955."
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) featuring Richard CrooksSept. 5, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Includes a note by Mildred Crooks with commentary on the 10 audiocassettes of Gilmour's Album.
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) featuring Richard CrooksOct. 24, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) featuring Richard CrooksOct. 15, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) featuring Richard CrooksSept. 28, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Second Anniversary Memorial
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) featuring Richard CrooksSept. 28 and 29, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) Golden ClassicsOct. 11, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) Apr. 17, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) July 10, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) Sept. 25, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Feb. 14, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Oct., 1943 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Oct., 1943 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Nov., 1943 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Nov. 20, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Dec. 18, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Jan. 8, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program) Dec. 11, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Metropolitan (Radio program) BBC. "Directors"Oct. 29, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Second of six hourly programs on B.B.C radio. Steane, John: host.
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. Acts I and II Jan. 13, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Metropolitan Opera. Pelletier, Wilfrid, 1896-1982, conductor. Performers: Moore, Grace 1898-1947 and Crooks, Richard.
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. Acts III, IV and VJan. 13, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Part IApril 6, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Metropolitan Broadcast
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Part IIApril 6, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon (selections) and Songs of FaithJan. 13, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    Metropolitan Opera. Pelletier, Wilfrid, 1896-1982, conductor. Songs of Faith. Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Selections. Messiah. Comfort ye, my people -- Samson. Total eclipse -- Judas Maccabaeus. Sound an alarm -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Selections. Paulus. Sei getreu bis in den Tod -- Elias. So ihr mich von ganzem Herzen suchet -- Dann werden die Gerechten -- Ave Maria -- Franck, C#233;sar, 1822-1890. Panis angelicus -- Burleigh, H. T. (Harry Thacker), 1866-1949. Were you there -- All through the night -- Huhn, Bruno. Invictus -- O'Hara, Geoffrey, 1882- There is no death
  - Richard Crooks sings for Eagle's weddingJune 14, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    O perfect love
  - Gilmour's Albums (CBC Radio Network, Canada) songs by Richard CrooksApril, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    Second memorial album.Romberg -- Prize song -- Firestone theme -- Because -- Lalo, Edouard, 1823-1892. Roi d'Ys -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Paulus. Be thou faithful -- For you with love
  - Easter Mass ServiceApril 6, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - The Art of Richard Crooks (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Conversation with Mildred CrooksDec. 1, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    with Sawka, Barbara and Koprowski, Richard
  - Interview with Mildred CrooksFeb. 3, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Conversation with Mildred CrooksOct. 22, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    with Mattis, Olivia. Primary subject: Antheil, George
- Audio-visual materials
  - Richard CrooksPanchromatic negative safety film; 35 mm (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Black and white #132 Griffin, Wayne
  - Richard CrooksEastman color negative; 35 mm; type 5251 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    #132 Griffin, Wayne and Tobin, George.
- Miscellany
  - Crooks Tosca posterSept. 20, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Hamburger Stadt Theater
  - Town Hall Concert. Among those presentJuly 30, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reproduction of an Anton Rubinstein portrait (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Engraving of Sarah Bernhardt's portrait1879 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Jules Bastien Lepage, engraver
  - Three envelopes annotated (Mildred Crooks handwriting) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Disc album with dedication (Othertype 19, Folder 6)
    Presented by the Texas Company to Richard Crooks. In grateful appreciation of his participation in the Metropolitan Opera Broadcast. Victor Records.
  - The Opera Game (Othertype 19, Folder 7)
    Opera question and answers by Ken Harris
  - Voice of Firestone Poster. Richard Crooks and Lawrence Tibbet. c.1 (Othertype 20, Folder 8)
  - Voice of Firestone Poster. Richard Crooks and Lawrence Tibbet. c.2 (Othertype 21, Folder 9)
  - Inaugural Committee District Building. Washington, D.CJan. 9, 1937 (Othertype 19, Folder 10)